AmbyrShae Calix

Process-oriented software engineer with 8+ years of experience building B2G & B2B SaaS products: 6 years as a FS engineer and 2 years as a TPM. Intrigued by product conceptualization and delivery, worked within engineering, UI/UX, and product management.

Experience

Lead FE & UI Engineer

eWorld Enterprise Solutions | Jul 2018 - Present

PHIMS I B2G SaaS

- Led FE development and UI/UX design and implemented Scrum, completing project wellahead of 3 year deadline
- Designed mockups using Adobe XD, reducing dev rework to 10%
- Conducted customer interviews, received feedback, and delivered iterative designs weekly
- Full-stack development using Vue.js & Sprint Boot to track thousands of vessels passing through Hawaii's 10 harbors
- Tested software using JUnit & JMeter, verifying accurate tariff rate calculations to process fees for over 8 million tons of cargo

Technical Product Manager

eWorld Enterprise Solutions | Mar 2021 - Mar 2023

BES | B2G SaaS

- Lead 80 person team in Scrum and improve processes to align project goals and client expectations
- Create strategic and business process models to use for 3-year roadmap
- Define 500+ tickets by translating customer needs into requirements and acceptance criteria
- Increased team velocity 100% by implementing Scrum
- Increased PR throughput 200% by creating code review standards and template
- Reduced bug percentage from 80% to 15% by utilizing 15% dev time to fixes and appointing "squasher" every sprint
- Document performance constraints to properly service 400,000 households and issue \$3 billion in benefits
- Daily cross-functional team collaboration to ensure clear communication across the product
- Review UI / UX mockups and provide weekly feedback for requirement accuracy

Software Engineer

GE Digital | Dec 2016 - Apr 2018

Field Vision | B2B Hybrid

- FS engineer on 100+ person, cross-functional team. Developed an offline-first, industrial IOT hybrid product
- Full-stack development using Angular & Sprint Boot to provide field service engineers a mobile app that can be used offline and a web app

Contact

504-356-3525

calix.shae@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ambyrshae

Education

Computer Science, B.S.

The University of New Orleans New Orleans, LA

Skills

Javascript V

Vue.js

Git

HTML / CSS

Spring Boot

Java

Web app

JUnit

Test driven development

Cross-functional team

Jira

Agile

Product management

Roadmapping

Process modeling

Kanban

Adobe XD

Scrum

UI / UX

SQL

API development

AngularJS

Object oriented design

Microservices

Jenkins

Linux